The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
B support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
B支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
VICTOR COSTAN: Any questions about the sorting methods
VICTOR COSTAN：有关排序方法的任何问题
that you want me to go over in that while I revise?
在我修改的同时，您要我过去吗？
OK.
好。
All right, sorting.
好吧，排序。
What sorting methods have we learned?
我们学到了什么分类方法？
Let's start from dumbest to smartest.
让我们从最笨拙到最聪明。
AUDIENCE: Merge sorting.
听众：合并排序。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, somewhere in the middle.
维克多·科斯坦：好的，在中间的某个地方。
Merge sort isn't very bad.
合并排序不是很糟糕。
What's the easiest method to sort?
最简单的排序方法是什么？
AUDIENCE: Insertion.
听众：插入。
VICTOR COSTAN: Insertion sort.
VICTOR COSTAN：插入排序。
Excellent.
优秀的。
All right.
好吧。
What else?
还有什么？
Heapsort.
堆排序。
And?
和？
I gave two away now.
我现在送了两个。
AUDIENCE: Counting.
听众：数数。
VICTOR COSTAN: Counting sort.
维克多·科斯坦：计数排序。
Very good.
很好。
And?
和？
Oh, wow.
哦，哇
If you don't even have the name of it.
如果您甚至没有名字。
So the last one is radix sort.
所以最后一个是基数排序。
What are the running times for these three
这三个的运行时间是多少
that you guys remember?
你们还记得吗？
AUDIENCE: Insertion sort is linearly one more.
听众：插入排序线性地又一。
It's bad.
这不好。
VICTOR COSTAN: I want to see our pseudocode for insertion sorts.
维克托·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：我想看看我们的用于插入排序的伪代码。
AUDIENCE: n squared.
听众：n平方。
AUDIENCE: Now that's really bad.
听众：现在真的很糟糕。
VICTOR COSTAN: So linear is as good as you could possibly get.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：线性尽可能好。
So sorting takes an array of random stuff
因此排序需要一系列随机的东西
and outputs an array of things in a sorted order.
并按排序的顺序输出一组事物。
The array is size n, so it has to output an array of size n.
该数组的大小为n，因此必须输出大小为n的数组。
If you can do an algorithm that runs in order n time,
如果您可以执行按n次运行的算法，
then that's the best you could possibly accomplish,
那就是你可能完成的最好的事情，
because you have output n elements.
因为您有输出n个元素。
So the best possible time you could get for sorting
因此，您可以获得最佳的排序时间
is theta of n.
是n的theta。
All right.
好吧。
How about merge sort?
合并排序如何？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: Thank you.
维克多·科斯坦：谢谢。
Heapsort.
堆排序。
AUDIENCE: Order h.
听众：订单h。
Order h is log n.
顺序h是对数n。
VICTOR COSTAN: Order h where h is log n.
维克多·波士坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：订购h，其中h为log n。
OK.
好。
And you're missing a factor.
而且您缺少一个因素。
So a heap operation takes order h, which is log n.
因此，堆操作的顺序为h，即日志n。
So if I have to insert a numbering in a heap
因此，如果我必须在堆中插入编号
or extract a number from a heap, that's log n.
或从堆中提取一个数字，即为log n。
In order to start an array, how many insertions do I do?
为了开始一个数组，我要插入多少个？
AUDIENCE: I think-- now I don't know.
听众：我想-现在我不知道。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Wild guess.
胡乱猜测。
AUDIENCE: n.
听众：
VICTOR COSTAN: Very good.
VICTOR COSTAN：很好。
See, there you go.
看，你去。
So you need to insert all your numbers in a heap
因此，您需要将所有数字插入到堆中
and then extract them one by one.
然后一一提取。
And you will get them in the correct order
您将以正确的顺序获得它们
that gives you the sorted results.
给您排序的结果。
So n log n.
所以n log n。
Does anyone remember what's special about these three
有谁记得这三个有什么特别之处
sorting methods that does not apply to the other two?
排序方法不适用于其他两个吗？
AUDIENCE: They're in place.
听众：他们到位了。
VICTOR COSTAN: Merge sort isn't quite in place.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：合并排序还不够。
If it would be in place, it would be perfect.
如果到位，那将是完美的。
There is actually a way of making in place merge sort,
实际上，有一种方法可以进行合并排序，
but it requires a PhD degree to understand that.
但是需要博士学位才​​能理解。
So we will not cover it in 6006, because I do not understand it.
所以我们不会在6006中进行介绍，因为我不理解。
So I couldn't explain it.
所以我无法解释。
So merge sort is not quite in place.
因此，合并排序并不十分到位。
Which one is in place?
哪一个到位？
AUDIENCE: Heapsort.
听众：Heapsort。
VICTOR COSTAN: Good.
维克多·科斯坦：好。
So heapsort is in place.
这样堆排序就位了。
Merge sort is not in place.
合并排序不到位。
And insertion sort is really slow,
而且插入排序真的很慢，
so we don't care that much about it.
所以我们不在乎。
So what's special about these three
那这三个有什么特别之处
that does not apply to these two?
那不适用于这两个？
AUDIENCE: You don't have to use integers.
听众：您不必使用整数。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
You don't have to use integers.
您不必使用整数。
What do they want to know instead
他们想知道些什么
about the things you use?
关于你用的东西？
So we'll call them keys.
所以我们称它们为钥匙。
AUDIENCE: You need to be able to compare them.
听众：您需要能够比较它们。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: You don't need to have a minimum
听众：您不需要最低要求
and a maximum integer.
和最大整数。
VICTOR COSTAN: So turns out, if you have a comparison operator,
VICTOR COSTAN：事实证明，如果您有比较运算符，
you will have a minimum and a maximum.
您将有一个最小值和最大值。
But that's complex abstract algebra
但这是复杂的抽象代数
that we don't need to worry about.
我们不必担心。
So you gave me the good answer, which
所以你给了我很好的答案，
is we use something called a comparison model.
我们使用一种称为比较模型的东西吗？
And in that model, you do not need
在这种模式下，您不需要
to know too much about your keys.
对您的钥匙了解太多。
So the elements in the area that you're sorting.
因此，您要排序的区域中的元素。
Your keys are blobs.
您的密钥是斑点。
And all they have to be able to do
他们必须要做的一切
is know-- if you have two of them--
知道-如果您有两个-
you have to know which one's greater.
您必须知道哪个更大。
That's it.
而已。
Nothing else.
没有其他的。
What's the problem with the comparison model?
比较模型有什么问题？
AUDIENCE: It takes time to compare things.
听众：比较事物需要时间。
It's like with everything.
就像一切。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
So we learned in lecture that there
所以我们在讲座中得知
is a lower bound for the comparison model.
是比较模型的下限。
And if you want to sort using nothing but this information,
如果您只想使用此信息进行排序，
that will take you at least n log n time.
这将至少花费n log n次。
You cannot do better than n log n if all you're using is
如果您正在使用的是
comparisons.
比较。
So in that respect, merge sort and heap sort are optimal.
因此，在这方面，合并排序和堆排序是最佳的。
If you want to stay within this model,
如果您想保持这种模式，
this is the best time you're going to get.
这是您将获得的最佳时间。
Does anyone know how you can implement this comparison model
有人知道您如何实现此比较模型
in Python?
在Python中？
So numbers respond to these operators, right?
数字对这些运算符有反应，对吗？
Actually, in Python this is equals equals.
实际上，在Python中，它等于equals。
What if I have a random object and I
如果我有一个随机物体并且我该怎么办
want to make it respond to these operators?
想使其对这些运营商做出反应？
So for example, I write merge sort.
因此，例如，我编写合并排序。
We wrote merge sort.
我们写了合并排序。
And now I have my own objects, my own keys
现在我有了自己的对象，自己的钥匙
which are not necessarily integers,
不一定是整数，
because that's why we like this.
因为这就是为什么我们喜欢这个。
And we want to make them respond to these operators.
我们想让他们对这些运营商做出回应。
So I can call merge sort on an array of them
所以我可以对它们的数组调用归并排序
and it will crash.
它将崩溃。
What do I have to do?
我需要做什么？
AUDIENCE: I mean, you have to give the keys
听众：我的意思是，你必须给钥匙
values that can be compared.
可以比较的值。
VICTOR COSTAN: So suppose this is my key class.
维克多·科斯坦：所以假设这是我的重点课。
AUDIENCE: This is lad, the lt, and gt.
听众：这是小伙子，lt和gt。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
There's a magical method in Python.
Python中有一个神奇的方法。
So there is the old school model,
所以有旧式的模式
which you might see in legacy code, which only works
您可能会在旧版代码中看到的
in Python 2.x, which is you define the method called
在Python 2.x中，您可以定义称为
cmp that takes self and other.
需要自我和其他的cmp。
And it has to return a number that's
它必须返回一个数字
either smaller than zero, equal to zero, or greater than zero.
小于零，等于零或大于零。
And this maps to this.
这映射到此。
So you'll see this in old code.
因此，您将在旧代码中看到这一点。
But you shouldn't use it in new code.
但是您不应该在新代码中使用它。
On this, you have a very good reason to.
因此，您有很好的理由。
Instead, the new model says that you
相反，新模型会说
define special methods called lt, which stands for less than.
定义称为lt的特殊方法，它代表小于。
So it's this guy.
所以就是这个人。
le, which is less or equal.
le，小于或等于。
gt, which is greater than.
gt，大于。
And ge, which is greater or equal.
与ge相等或更大。
And if you look at our code for pieces two and three,
如果您看一下第二和第三部分的代码，
we have some objects that pretend they're keys.
我们有一些假装它们是钥匙的物体。
And we have to define these methods.
而且我们必须定义这些方法。
Also, when you define these, it's
另外，当您定义这些时，
a good idea to define eq for equality comparison.
为相等比较定义等式的好主意。
And ne, which is this guy.
ne，这是那个家伙。
So these also take self and other key
因此这些也需要自我和其他关键
that you're comparing with.
与您进行比较
And they return true or false.
并且它们返回true或false。
So this will help you understand the code better.
因此，这将帮助您更好地理解代码。
All right, so with relatively little work,
好吧，所以工作比较少，
you can have any wild object you want act as a key.
您可以让任何想要用作键的野生对象。
And then you have insertion sort,
然后您有插入排序，
merge sort, heapsort, heaps, binary trees, AVLs.
合并排序，堆排序，堆，二叉树，AVL。
Everything works, because everything uses the comparison
一切正常，因为一切都使用比较
model.
模型。
The problem is this n log n bound.
问题是此n log n绑定。
It's not as fast as the best possible sorting algorithm
它没有最好的排序算法快
you could come up with.
你可以想出。
This is slower than this.
这比这慢。
So that's why we have to break out of the comparison model.
这就是为什么我们必须突破比较模型。
And we have to look into these boxes and get more information,
我们必须调查这些框并获取更多信息，
so that we can write faster sorting algorithms.
这样我们就可以编写更快的排序算法。
Does anyone remember the running time for counting sort?
有人记得计数时间吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] again?
听众：再次[听不清]？
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: n plus e.
听众：n加e。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Let's remember how counting sort looks like.
让我们记住计数排序是什么样的。
Let's get this array that-- that should be enough-- four, one,
让我们得到这个数组-应该足够了-四个，一个，
three, two, three.
三二三
How do we sort it using counting sort?
我们如何使用计数排序对其进行排序？
AUDIENCE: We initialize an array of all the possible values.
听众：我们初始化所有可能值的数组。
VICTOR COSTAN: Very good.
VICTOR COSTAN：很好。
Very good.
很好。
So counting sort needs to know something about your values,
因此，计算排序需要了解您的价值观，
right?
对？
It makes an assumption.
它做一个假设。
And the assumption is that these values
假设这些值
are integers from 0 to, say, k minus 1.
是从0到k减去1的整数。
So you have k possible values.
因此，您有k个可能的值。
And they don't really have to be these as long
他们真的不需要那么久
as you can map them to these numbers.
因为您可以将它们映射到这些数字。
So we are going to initialize an array.
因此，我们将初始化一个数组。
Let's say this is an array.
假设这是一个数组。
And zero, one.
零，一。
So zero, one, two, three, four, five.
所以零，一，二，三，四，五。
So we're going to initialize it with--
因此，我们将使用-
AUDIENCE: Oh, zeroes.
听众：哦，零。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
And then?
接着？
AUDIENCE: Iterative over our list sort
观众：遍历我们的清单排序
incrementing the corresponding value to each key in your--
将相应的值递增到您的-
VICTOR COSTAN: So which one am I incrementing here?
维克多·科斯坦：那我要增加哪一个？
AUDIENCE: Pardon?
听众：对不起？
VICTOR COSTAN: Which one am I incrementing here?
维克多·科斯坦：我要在这里增加哪一位？
AUDIENCE: Zero ne through four.
听众：零到四之间。
One.
一。
VICTOR COSTAN: Three, two.
维克多·科斯坦：三，二。
And then?
接着？
AUDIENCE: Three n.
听众：三名。
So this becomes a two.
这样就变成了两个。
And what do I do now?
我现在该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Reiterate over that-- I don't know.
听众：重申一下-我不知道。
I don't know what to call that identity [INAUDIBLE] almost?
我几乎不知道该身份是什么[听不清]？
OK, an array.
好，一个数组。
Printing into your output array one one, one two, two threes,
一一，一二，二三三打印到输出数组中
one four.
一四
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So there's no zeroes and now fives.
因此，没有零，现在没有五。
So one one, one two, one three, and one four.
所以一一，一二，一三和一四。
OK, so far so good.
好的，到目前为止很好。
This is great.
这很棒。
There's one thing that's missing.
缺少一件事。
For counting sort and for other sorting algorithms,
对于计数排序和其他排序算法，
we care about the property called stability.
我们关心的是稳定性。
And stability means that if you have
稳定性意味着如果您有
two equal keys, or at least two keys
两个相等的键，或至少两个键
that look equal to the sorting algorithm,
看起来与排序算法相同
they might be different objects, because they
它们可能是不同的对象，因为它们
might be implementing that.
可能正在实施。
The one that shows up first in the input
在输入中首先出现的那个
should also show up first in the output.
还应该首先显示在输出中。
And that requires particular care,
那需要特别注意
because you can't just look at the keys
因为你不能只看按键
from your sorting perspective and know
从您的排序角度了解
which one's supposed to go where.
哪个应该去哪里。
You have to remember where they were in the input.
您必须记住它们在输入中的位置。
So if this guy is 3a, and this guy is 3b,
因此，如果这个人是3a，而这个人是3b，
I can't use this approach anymore, right?
我不能再使用这种方法了，对吧？
Because when I'm outputting here, all I know
因为当我在这里输出时，我所知道的
is I have to output a three.
是我必须输出三个。
I don't have any other information
我没有其他信息
associated with the key.
与密钥关联。
So instead, I have to do something smarter.
因此，我必须做些更聪明的事情。
AUDIENCE: Either replace your array with a 2-D array.
听众：用二维阵列替换阵列。
Or I think better would be to replace
或者我认为最好是更换
each value with a length list.
每个值都有一个长度列表。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So we can replace each value with a length list, which
因此我们可以将每个值替换为长度列表
would have the keys that map to it, right.
将具有映射到它的键，对。
So here I would have a one.
所以在这里我要一个。
Here I would have a two.
在这里，我有两个。
Here I would have 3a, and then 3b.
在这里，我将有3a，然后是3b。
and here I would have a four.
我这里有四个
So then I can go through these and output them the right way.
这样我就可以检查这些内容并以正确的方式输出它们。
OK, now suppose I'm writing this in C.
OK，现在假设我正在用C编写此代码。
Suppose I'm in a low level language.
假设我使用的是低级语言。
And I'm in a low level language because I'm
我使用低级语言，因为我
hired by one of these startups that are doing NoSQL databases.
由从事NoSQL数据库的这些初创公司之一雇用。
And they're writing everything in C
他们正在用C编写所有内容
to make their things really fast.
使他们的事情真正快速。
So I'm writing an index that uses counting sort.
所以我正在写一个使用计数排序的索引。
I don't have length lists, because if I'm writing in C,
我没有长度列表，因为如果我用C编写，
I have to write my own.
我必须写我自己的。
And that's hard.
那很难。
So I want to implement this in another way.
所以我想用另一种方式来实现。
Length lists are hard.
长度列表很难。
What would I do instead?
我该怎么办？
Can anyone think of another way?
谁能想到另一种方式？
AUDIENCE: I think you can decrement the values
听众：我认为您可以降低价值
for the C in the array that you have,
对于您拥有的数组中的C，
where you have to type the culture of each anyway.
无论如何，您必须在其中键入每种语言的文化。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so you have the right idea.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，所以您有一个正确的想法。
You're missing one step.
您错过了一步。
So I'll give everyone else a hint
所以我会给其他人一个提示
so that everyone can catch up.
这样每个人都可以赶上。
So what I want to do is I want to take this and transform it
所以我想做的就是接受并转化它
into something that allows me to go through the keys.
可以让我通过按键的东西。
So I know I have five keys here.
所以我知道我这里有五把钥匙。
I'm going to make an output array of five elements.
我将制作一个包含五个元素的输出数组。
And I want to be able to see four and know
我希望能够看到四个并知道
that it belongs here.
它属于这里。
See one, know that it belongs here.
看到一个，知道它属于这里。
See 3a, know that it belongs here.
参见3a，知道它属于这里。
Then probably update the value associated with three.
然后可能会更新与三关联的值。
See two, know that it belongs here.
看到两个，知道它属于这里。
And then when I see 3b, know that it belongs here.
然后，当我看到3b时，知道它属于这里。
So I want to look, when I get to 3a, I want to look inside here.
所以我想看，当我到达3a时，我想看这里。
And I want this to tell me that 3 belongs here,
我想告诉我3属于这里，
3a belongs here.
3a属于这里。
So what would the position of 3a be?
那么3a的位置将是什么？
That's not good, right?
那不好，对吗？
Let's call this c instead so that I can say 3a be.
让我们将其称为c，这样我可以说3a是。
So how would I define the position
那我怎么定义位置
using the sorted property?
使用排序的属性？
3a should go in the index that is how many keys smaller than 3
3a应该进入比3小几个键的索引
there are.
有。
So if I can look through here and see
所以，如果我可以看这里
how many keys do I have that are smaller than 3,
我有多少个小于3的钥匙，
this is where 3a needs to go.
这是3a需要去的地方。
If I look at four, there are four keys
如果我看四个，有四个关键
that are smaller than four.
小于四个。
So it needs to go in position four.
因此，它需要排在第四位。
AUDIENCE: Well, that almost seems more like a compare.
听众：好吧，这似乎更像是一个比较。
I'm guessing that makes it-- I think
我猜是那样的-我认为
it's kind of a comparison model.
这是一个比较模型。
But you're saying is it greater than.
但是您是说它大于。
So it's not really counting sort anymore as much.
因此，它不再真正地计算排序。
VICTOR COSTAN: Well, I'm telling you
维克多·科斯坦：好吧，我告诉你
I can compute that using this.
我可以用这个来计算。
So I can use the counting sort algorithm
所以我可以使用计数排序算法
and change this array a little bit so that I can do this trick
并稍微更改此数组，以便我可以完成此操作
and know what goes where.
知道去哪里。
AUDIENCE: You already mentioned using a 2-D array.
听众：您已经提到过使用二维数组。
VICTOR COSTAN: But a 2-D array would be too much.
维克多·科斯坦：但是，二维阵列实在太多了。
In the end, I will be changing this in place.
最后，我将更改此位置。
So no extra space except for this array of size k.
因此，除了此大小为k的数组之外，没有其他空间。
But let's not worry about changing it in place right now.
但是，不必担心现在就更改它。
Let's say we're going to make another array of size k.
假设我们要制作另一个大小为k的数组。
So I want it to tell me that-- I guess I don't care about this--
所以我想告诉我-我想我不在乎-
but I want it to tell me that one, the first one
但我想告诉我一个，第一个
should go here, the first two should go here,
应该去这里，前两个应该去这里，
the first three should go here, the first four should go here.
前三个应该在这里，前四个应该在这里。
How do I do that?
我怎么做？
AUDIENCE: Well, you could make that array, right.
听众：好吧，你可以做那个数组，对。
VICTOR COSTAN: But how do I compute it?
维克多·科斯坦：但是我怎么计算呢？
AUDIENCE: While you're making this one,
听众：在制作这个的时候
you can start filling that one in.
您可以开始填充那个。
But while you're making the top one.
但是当您进入第一名时。
VICTOR COSTAN: Can I?
维克多·科斯坦：我可以吗？
AUDIENCE: It would be like insertion sort though, kind of.
听众：有点像插入类。
So you come across the four.
所以您遇到了四个。
You put it in there, because you know how many there are.
您将其放入其中，因为您知道其中有多少个。
But that doesn't make a lot of sense.
但这没有多大意义。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah, OK.
维克多·科斯坦：是的，好的。
So let's abandon that route.
因此，让我们放弃那条路线。
Let's think of something else.
让我们想一想。
AUDIENCE: Could you populate the array
听众：您可以填充数组吗
with the number of elements that are less than that [INAUDIBLE]?
元素数量少于[听不清]的元素？
VICTOR COSTAN: So intuitively, I want
VICTOR COSTAN：直观地说，我要
this to tell me how many elements there
告诉我那里有多少元素
are that are smaller than two.
小于两个。
This should tell me the number of elements
这应该告诉我元素的数量
there are that are smaller than three, so on and so forth.
有小于三个的，依此类推。
OK, how would I compute that?
好的，我该怎么计算呢？
Let's see what it's supposed to be.
让我们看看它应该是什么。
Let's fill it out with real values.
让我们用真实值填写它。
AUDIENCE: Zero.
听众：零。
VICTOR COSTAN: Zero.
维克多·科斯坦：零。
How many elements smaller than one?
多少个元素小于一个？
AUDIENCE: Zero.
听众：零。
VICTOR COSTAN: How many elements smaller than two?
VICTOR COSTAN：小于两个的元素有多少？
AUDIENCE: One.
听众：一。
VICTOR COSTAN: How many elements smaller than three?
VICTOR COSTAN：小于三个的元素有多少？
AUDIENCE: Two.
听众：两个。
It's a cumulative sum.
这是累计金额。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: On the array above.
听众：在上面的阵列上。
VICTOR COSTAN: So this is how many elements smaller
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：这就是缩小了多少个元素
than four?
比四个？
Or how many elements smaller than 5 4?
或多少个元素小于5 4？
OK.
好。
what's the difference between these two guys?
这两个家伙有什么区别？
AUDIENCE: One.
听众：一。
VICTOR COSTAN: What's the difference between these two
VICTOR COSTAN：两者之间有什么区别
guys?
伙计们？
AUDIENCE: One.
听众：一。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah, you're right.
维克多·科斯坦：是的，您是对的。
Sorry.
抱歉。
Thank you.
谢谢。
What's the difference between these two guys?
这两个家伙有什么区别？
AUDIENCE: Two.
听众：两个。
One.
一。
VICTOR COSTAN: And what's the difference between these two
VICTOR COSTAN：两者之间有什么区别
guys?
伙计们？
AUDIENCE: Zero.
听众：零。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, What did I just write here?
维克多·科斯坦：好的，我刚才在这里写了什么？
AUDIENCE: Same series up there.
听众：同一系列。
AUDIENCE: Array.
听众：数组。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So this guy is zero, right, because there's no element
所以这个人是零，对，因为没有元素
that-- there's nothing that's smaller to the smallest key.
那-没有什么比最小的键更小了。
And then this guy is whatever was here plus this almost.
然后这个家伙就是这里的一切加上几乎所有的东西。
So the difference between this guy and this guy is this.
所以这个家伙和这个家伙之间的区别就是这样。
AUDIENCE: So why go through an array?
听众：那么为什么要遍历数组呢？
I mean, why did you bother?
我的意思是，你为什么要打扰？
Why do we make a new array?
我们为什么要制作一个新的阵列？
Because we could just get that information.
因为我们可以获取该信息。
VICTOR COSTAN: Making a new array
VICTOR COSTAN：制作新阵列
so that we can see how to compute it.
这样我们就可以看到如何计算它。
So now we're going to try to right pseudocode that
所以现在我们将尝试纠正伪代码
does this in place.
做到这一点。
So suppose this array is a and this
所以假设这个数组是一个
array is pass for position.
数组传递位置。
And suppose-- sorry, not this array.
并假设-抱歉，不是这个数组。
This array is a.
这个数组是一个。
This array is pass.
该数组是合格的。
And I start with this.
我从这个开始。
And I want to end up with this.
我要结束这个。
So let's try to write the pseudocode for counting sort.
因此，让我们尝试编写用于计数排序的伪代码。
Counting sort with an array a.
用数组计数排序a。
I'm not going to write the first two lines that produce this.
我不会写产生这种情况的前两行。
Let's transform this to this.
让我们将其转换为此。
How would I do that?
我该怎么做？
AUDIENCE: Initialize an array of the same size.
听众：初始化大小相同的数组。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Can we try to do it in place?
我们可以尝试就地做到吗？
AUDIENCE: Sure.
听众：好的。
VICTOR COSTAN: How do we do it in place?
维克多·科斯坦：我们如何做到这一点？
AUDIENCE: You could, well for four, you get the four.
听众：四个人，你可以得到四个。
You're like, oh, I haven't encountered anything below me.
你就像，哦，我还没遇到什么。
So you put it in zero initially for four.
因此，您最初将其置零为四。
And then you get a one.
然后你得到一个。
And you're like, oh, I haven't gotten anything below me.
而且您就像，哦，我什么都没得到。
But I forget to keep track of the fact
但是我忘了跟踪事实
that you have to iterate a whole list ever single time
您必须一次遍历整个列表
you get a new input.
您会得到一个新的输入。
VICTOR COSTAN: So I don't want to do that,
维克多·科斯坦：所以我不想那样做，
because that's n squared.
因为那是平方。
AUDIENCE: What you need to do is keep a running sum.
听众：您需要做的是保持连续不断的增长。
Is it a register?
它是寄存器吗？
Is that what you do call it?
那就是你所说的吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Running sum.
维克多·科斯坦：总计。
I like running sum.
我喜欢总和。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
Keep a running sum of--
保持-
VICTOR COSTAN: Sums always start at zero, right?
维克多·科斯坦：总和总是从零开始，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
So you keep zero at-- you take the value
所以您将零保持在-您取值
in each index of that array and add it to sum.
在该数组的每个索引中，并将其加和。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So for i iterating from zero to-- so you
所以我从零迭代到
want each value in this array, right?
想要这个数组中的每个值，对不对？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: So it's going to iterate from zero to what?
VICTOR COSTAN：那么它将从零迭代到什么？
How many elements do I have there?
我在那里有几个元素？
AUDIENCE: Length k.
听众：长度k。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, almost.
维克多·科斯坦：好的，差不多。
So we're using Python numbering, which is zero base indexing.
因此，我们正在使用Python编号，即零基索引。
The indices look like this.
索引看起来像这样。
So it's zero to--
所以-
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: Very good.
VICTOR COSTAN：很好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
And you said I'm going to add the elements to a sum.
你说我要把这些元素加起来。
So sum is sum plus position of i.
因此，总和就是i的和。
OK.
好。
And then?
接着？
AUDIENCE: The replace is the [INAUDIBLE].
听众：替换为[听不清]。
So zero should be zero still.
所以零应该仍然是零。
One should be the sum after evaluating zero.
评估为零后，总和应为1。
You'll need a temp variable.
您将需要一个临时变量。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: You'll need to graph position i when in temp.
听众：在温度下，您需要绘制位置i的图。
VICTOR COSTAN: Temp is position i.
COSTAN COSTAN：温度在位置i。
AUDIENCE: Then say position i is sum before incremental sums.
听众：然后说位置i是总和，然后是增量和。
No.
没有。
That's not it at all.
根本不是。
VICTOR COSTAN: Really?
维克多·科斯坦：真的吗？
AUDIENCE: We'll have to say that sum is sum plus temp.
听众：我们不得不说总和是总和加上临时工。
That is going to work.
那将起作用。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
How does everyone else feel about this?
其他人对此感觉如何？
Does it make sense?
是否有意义？
AUDIENCE: Not really.
听众：不是。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] temporary blast [INAUDIBLE]
听众：[听不清]临时爆炸[听不清]
previous adjuration, because-- so when you first started,
以前的裁决，因为-因此，当您第一次开始时，
it's the very initial case that doesn't work.
这是最初的情况，不起作用。
So like, if you're in the first column, everything's fine.
就像，如果您在第一列中，一切都很好。
Then you go to column one.
然后转到第一列。
You're looking at everything to the left of it.
您正在查看左侧的所有内容。
It's still going to be zero.
它仍将为零。
Then you go to the second column,
然后转到第二列，
but you already overwrote the previous column.
但是您已经覆盖了上一专栏。
So you need to store somehow the-- I don't know.
因此，您需要以某种方式存储-我不知道。
It's just the initial case from when it first
这只是第一次的最初情况
goes from zero to an actual qualified number.
从零到实际合格数字。
Because otherwise, you're just going
因为否则，你只是去
to get like zero, zero, zero.
得到零，零，零
And you just overwrite.
而您只是覆盖。
AUDIENCE: Can you start [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：您可以开始[听不清]吗？
Was that before you changed?
那是在您改变之前吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Sorry, I'm getting confused.
抱歉，我很困惑。
This is getting hard.
这越来越难了。
I will show you a trick to make life easier.
我将向您展示使生活更轻松的窍门。
I'm going to put-- how many elements do I have here?
我要说的是-我在这里有多少个元素？
Five, right?
五对吧
So I'm going to put a five here after the array.
因此，我将在阵列后放置5。
And then I'm going to ask you, what's this difference.
然后我要问你，这有什么区别。
AUDIENCE: Zero.
听众：零。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So now we have this whole array.
所以现在我们有了整个数组。
Can people see what's going on here.?
人们可以看到这里发生了什么吗？
So instead of starting at the beginning,
因此，与其从头开始，
I'm going to start at the end.
我将从结尾开始。
And I'm going to know-- I know for sure there are n elements.
我要知道-我肯定知道有n个元素。
Therefore, the index of this guy is n minus--
因此，这个人的指数是n减去-
so the index of the last key is n minus how many keys I
所以最后一个键的索引是n减去我有多少个键
have with this value.
有这个价值。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: But you're iterating over an order, right?
听众：但是您要遍历一个订单，对吗？
So we can't just take the whole thing
所以我们不能只拿整个东西
and say we're going to shift it over to the right.
并说我们将其移至右侧。
VICTOR COSTAN: How about--
维克多·科斯坦：怎么样-
AUDIENCE: And you're going through left to right.
听众：而且您正在经历从左到右的过程。
You'll only know what you see thus far.
您只会知道到目前为止所看到的。
VICTOR COSTAN: How about going it for ai from n minus 1 to 0.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：ai从n减1到0的情况如何。
Will it work then?
那会行吗？
So what would I write?
那我会写什么呢？
AUDIENCE: But isn't that super inefficient?
听众：但是那不是超级低效吗？
Because then you're starting looking at the whole list.
因为那样您便开始查看整个列表。
And then you're sort of, rather than just
然后你有点，而不只是
looking at the previous sum that you just-- the cumulative.
查看您之前的总和-累计。
So your first adjuration, you have
因此，您的第一个裁决是
to add up everything that you see.
汇总您看到的所有内容。
Like adjuration, you have to add everything up.
就像裁决一样，您必须将所有内容加起来。
VICTOR COSTAN: So if I add everything up here,
维克多·科斯坦：所以，如果我在这里添加所有内容，
what's the result going to be?
结果将是什么？
AUDIENCE: Five.
听众：五。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
What's five?
五点什么？
So this counts how many zero keys
所以这算出多少个零键
I've seen, how many one keys I've seen,
我看过，我看过多少个键，
how many two keys I've seen, so on and so forth.
我看过多少个两个键，依此类推。
So in total--
所以总共
AUDIENCE: So you're subtracting
听众：所以你减去
VICTOR COSTAN: It's how many keys I've seen.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：我已经看过多少把钥匙。
All this, the sum of all these, is how many keys I've sent.
所有这些加起来就是我发送了多少个密钥。
How many keys do I have?
我有多少把钥匙？
AUDIENCE: Five.
听众：五。
For each one you see, you can just--
对于您看到的每个人，您都可以-
VICTOR COSTAN: So who's five?
维克多·科斯坦：那五个是谁？
It's the length of this guy, right?
这是这个人的长度，对吧？
And we usually call that n.
我们通常称其为n。
So when we're doing sorting, this is n.
因此，当我们进行排序时，该值为n。
So maybe it's less confusing.
因此，也许它不那么令人困惑。
Oh, I already used n in two places.
哦，我已经在两个地方使用过n了。
So I guess that's it.
所以我想就是这样。
I could say the length of a, but there you go.
我可以说a的长度，但是你去了。
So I could do the thing that we're going through before.
所以我可以做我们之前正在做的事情。
I could figure out my temp variables.
我可以弄清楚我的临时变量。
And I could make it work.
我可以使它工作。
Or I could do this.
或者我可以这样做。
AUDIENCE: I think it's the same though, isn't it?
听众：我想是一样的，不是吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yup.
维克多·波士坦：是的。
It's the same thing, except I think this is easier to write.
是同一件事，除了我认为这更容易编写。
Does anyone want to help me write this?
有人想帮我写这个吗？
AUDIENCE: Maybe doing once you're
听众：也许一旦你
starting with the top array, and then finding the bottom one.
从顶部的数组开始，然后找到底部的数组。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
Well, you just-- you start with the first one
好吧，您只是-从第一个开始
and the one ahead of it.
和前面的那个
And oh, I mean starting with the top right.
哦，我的意思是从右上角开始。
Sorry.
抱歉。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so I have this.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，我有这个。
And then what do I do?
然后我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：[听不清]？
Oh, so you're starting from the back.
哦，所以您从背面开始。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: Well, then you just compare that to-- I mean,
听众：好吧，那么你可以将其与-我的意思是，
you're going to start with zero difference.
您将从零差开始。
If you have-- well you don't have any of those last keys,
如果您有-那么您没有任何这些最后的钥匙，
so you'd be able to start with a zero.
因此您可以从零开始。
VICTOR COSTAN: So what's the difference between five
VICTOR COSTAN：那么五个之间有什么区别
here, which is n, and this guy?
这是n，还有这个家伙？
What is this?
这是什么？
AUDIENCE: It's going to be zero.
听众：它将为零。
VICTOR COSTAN: But what is it?
维克多·科斯坦：但是那是什么？
Why is it zero?
为什么为零？
So this one's zero, this one's one, this one's two.
所以这个为零，这个为一，这个为二。
What is this?
这是什么？
It's the last guy here, right?
这是这里的最后一个人，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah, yeah.
听众：是的，是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: So this is pass of n minus 1.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：这是n减1的通过。
And this is pass of n minus 2, so on and so forth.
这是n减2的通过，依此类推。
So to get from n to the value here,
所以要从n到这里的值，
I have to subtract this guy.
我要减去这个家伙。
AUDIENCE: Pass of i.
听众：通过i。
VICTOR COSTAN: Pass of i.
维克多·波士坦：通过i。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Very good.
很好。
AUDIENCE: And then update sum.
听众：然后更新总和。
Sum equals a pos value.
总和等于pos值。
VICTOR COSTAN: Sweet.
维克多·科斯坦：甜。
No temp variables, aside from this, I guess.
我猜除了这个，没有临时变量。
How does this look like?
看起来如何？
Do people get it?
人们明白了吗？
AUDIENCE: You're subtracting positive i,
听众：您要减去正数i，
or you're subtracting a of i.
或者您要减去i。
AUDIENCE: It's all one array.
听众：全都是一个阵列。
AUDIENCE: It's the same thing.
听众：是同一回事。
That's right.
那就对了。
VICTOR COSTAN: So a is this array. a is the input array.
维克多·科斯坦：所以这个数组。 a是输入数组。
And pass is this guy.
通过的是这个人。
And this is pass before the four loop.
这是在四个循环之前通过的。
And this is pass after the four loop.
这是四个循环之后通过的。
So I guess this is pass zero.
所以我猜这是通过零。
And this is pass one.
这是第一关。
And here, we start with pass zero.
在这里，我们从传递零开始。
This, we end up with pass one.
这样，我们就获得了第一关。
OK
好
So we're able to compute this.
这样我们就可以计算出这一点。
There are many ways of doing this, but in the end,
这样做的方法很多，但最后，
you want an array that looks like that.
您想要一个看起来像这样的数组。
This is counting sort.
这是计数排序。
This is the hard part of counting sort, coming up
这是计数排序的难点，即将到来
with that array.
那个数组。
Once you come up with that array, you're golden.
一旦提出该阵列，您就很成功。
So let's see that we're golden and produce an output array
因此，让我们看一下我们是金色的，并产生一个输出数组
with the keys in the right order.
以正确的顺序排列按键。
So say we have an array called output.
可以这么说，我们有一个称为输出的数组。
And this is going to have these keys in the right order.
这将使这些键以正确的顺序排列。
What's the pseudocode for that?
伪代码是什么？
First, I'm going to create a new array.
首先，我将创建一个新数组。
And I'm going to initialize it with n NIL values.
我将使用n个NIL值对其进行初始化。
Then what do I do?
那我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Iterate over a.
听众：迭代一个。
VICTOR COSTAN: Very good.
VICTOR COSTAN：很好。
For-- nah, it's too low.
因为，那太低了。
Let's do it here.
让我们在这里做。
AUDIENCE: i of a.
听众：我是。
From zero to n minus 1.
从零到n减1。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
What do I do?
我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: Out of [INAUDIBLE] has to be-- oh,
观众：[听不清]必须是哦，
can we modify pass one as we go?
我们可以在进行时修改通行证吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: So you could say, out of pos one--
观众：所以您可以说，在第一个位置中，
VICTOR COSTAN: So by the way, this is pos.
维克多·科斯坦：顺便说一句，这是pos。
The reason I label them with zero and one,
我将它们标记为零和一的原因，
so we're doing the change in place.
因此，我们正在进行适当的更改。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
VICTOR COSTAN: The reason I labeled
VICTOR COSTAN：我标记的原因
them is to say that this is what pos
他们是说这是pos
is before we going into the loop.
在我们进入循环之前。
This is what pos is afterwards.
这就是pos之后的事情。
But it's a single array.
但这是一个数组。
So let's call it pos.
所以我们称它为pos。
So out of pos of--
所以出于以下原因
AUDIENCE: Pos of i equals a to the i.
受众：i的位置等于i。
Positive i plus pos squared.
正数加正数平方。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yup.
维克多·波士坦：是的。
And I'm going to use the CLRS, the way
我将使用CLRS
which makes me write more.
这让我写得更多。
So how this work?
那么如何工作？
I have the survey here.
我在这里进行调查。
I start at four.
我从四点开始。
What's pos of four?
四个的pos是多少？
AUDIENCE: Four.
听众：四。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right, so I'm going
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，我要走了
to write this as position four.
将此写为位置四。
I should probably make this a proper array.
我可能应该将其设置为适当的数组。
One two, three, four, five.
一二三四五。
So at four, I write four.
所以我四点钟就写四点
And then I increment this guy to become five.
然后我将这个人增加到五个。
Then I get to one.
然后我进入一个。
So I look at pos of--
所以我看一下-
AUDIENCE: One.
听众：一。
VICTOR COSTAN: And that is zero.
维克多·科斯坦：那是零。
So I'm going to write one at position zero.
所以我要在零位置写一个。
And I'm going to increment it.
我将增加它。
Then I get to 3a.
然后我到达3a。
I look at positive 3.
我看积极3。
It says 2.
它说2。
So I'm going to write 3a here and increment this.
所以我要在这里写3a并增加它。
Then I get to two.
然后我到两个。
Pos of two is--
Pos为两个
AUDIENCE: One.
听众：一。
VICTOR COSTAN: One.
维克多·科斯坦：一。
So I write two here.
所以我在这里写两个。
Pos of two becomes two.
两个的位置变成两个。
Then I have 3c, which is pos of 3 is now 3.
然后我有3c，现在3的pos是3。
It's not two anymore.
不再是两个了。
So yay, I'm not overwriting 3a.
所以，我不会覆盖3a。
That's good.
那很好。
And this becomes four.
这变成四个。
Are people getting what just happened here?
人们了解这里发生的事情了吗？
AUDIENCE: Wait, why didn't [INAUDIBLE] to just basically
听众：等等，为什么不[听不清]基本上
train the next array into an index binder?
将下一个数组训练成索引绑定器？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
So this guy tells me if I have a key,
所以这个人告诉我是否有钥匙，
where do I write it in here?
我在哪里写呢？
So these start out with pointers to the first element that
因此，这些开始于指向第一个元素的指针
would store that key value.
将存储该键值。
And when I store a key, say when I start 3a, when I get to 3c,
当我存储密钥时，比如说我从3a开始，到3c，
I don't want to store it in the same place.
我不想将其存储在同一位置。
So I have to increment that.
所以我必须增加它。
I have to say, yo, I wrote 3a at position two.
我必须说，哟，我在第二位置写了3a。
So next time, write it-- next time you
所以下次再写一次
see a three, right it at the position following that.
看到三个，将其放在紧随其后的位置。
And that's what this guy does.
这就是那个家伙所做的。
So this is the relatively easy part.
因此，这是相对容易的部分。
And this is the hard magic in counting sort.
这是计数排序中的难点。
So how are people feeling about it now?
那么人们现在对此感觉如何？
Any nods, or is still confusing as hell?
有没有点头，还是仍然感到困惑？
AUDIENCE: It's a lot.
听众：很多。
I'm confused.
我糊涂了。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Well what should we do?
那么我们该怎么办？
Do you guys want to ask more questions?
你们想问更多问题吗？
Do you want to run through another example?
您是否想通过另一个例子？
Do you want to try to see how this becomes useful in radix
您是否想尝试一下这在基数中变得有用吗
sort, so that you're motivated to figure it out on your own?
排序，以便您有动力自行解决？
What would make more sense?
什么更有意义？
All right.
好吧。
Who wants to do more count sort?
谁想做更多的计数排序？
Who wants to do some radix sort.
谁想做一些基数排序。
All right.
好吧。
Radix sort it is.
基数排序。
Next time you want to move on, tell me understood
下次您要继续前进时，请告诉我
and I'll believe you.
我会相信你的
And it'll look good on tape.
在磁带上看起来会很好。
Two, three--
二三 -
AUDIENCE: You're not supposed to tell us
听众：你不应该告诉我们
that there's a camera in here.
那里有一台照相机。
VICTOR COSTAN: One, four.
维克多·科斯坦：一，四。
I think you're supposed to know, because otherwise you
我认为您应该知道，因为否则
don't know that we're violating your rights.
不知道我们侵犯了您的权利。
Two, four--
二四
AUDIENCE: This is out the door.
听众：这是门外。
VICTOR COSTAN: One, two, four, three, two, one, four, three.
维克多·科斯坦：一，二，四，三，二，一，四，三。
And one more.
还有一个。
One, two, three, four.
一二三四。
So this is to refresh your memory.
因此，这是为了刷新您的记忆。
What do keys look like in merge and radix sort?
合并和基数排序中的键是什么样的？
So in concert, the keys have to be numbers from 0 to k minus 1.
因此，一致地，密钥必须是0到k减去1的数字。
How about merge sort?
合并排序如何？
What do keys look like?
钥匙是什么样的？
So radix sort says that a key is a sequence of digits.
因此，基数排序表示键是数字序列。
Say you have d digits in a key.
假设您的密钥中有d位数字。
But then each digit isn't necessarily a base 10 digit
但是，然后每个数字不一定是以10为基数的数字
like we're used to.
就像我们习惯了
Each digit is in base k.
每个数字以k为底。
So each digit can be from 0 to k minus 1.
因此，每个数字可以从0到k减去1。
And we're using base k.
而且我们正在使用基数k。
How many keys can I represent this way?
我可以用这种方式代表多少个钥匙？
So if you have numbers of n digits in base k,
因此，如果以k为底的数字为n位数字，
what's the biggest number that we can represent,
我们能代表的最大数字是多少
or how many numbers can we represent with that?
或我们可以用多少个数字表示？
AUDIENCE: n to the k.
听众：n至k。
No, d to the k.
不，d到k。
Right?
对？
VICTOR COSTAN: Almost.
维克多·科斯坦：差不多了。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] the d.
听众：[听不清] d。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So if our base is two, like if we're using bits,
因此，如果我们的底数是2，就像我们在使用位，
then our base is two.
那么我们的基数是两个
And if I have eight bits, then two to the eight.
如果我有八位，那么二到八位。
Cool.
凉。
So if I add one more digit, I get
所以如果再加上一位，我得到
to multiply the number of keys I represent by k.
将我代表的键数乘以k。
How do I radix sort?
我如何对基数排序？
Does anyone remember?
有人记得吗？
AUDIENCE: We checked the log base k of everything.
观众：我们检查了所有内容的对数基数k。
I guess log base d.
我猜对数为D。
Oh, k.
哦，k。
It's based in--
它基于-
VICTOR COSTAN: No.
维克多·科斯坦：不。
That would be hard math.
那将是很难的数学运算。
We don't do hard math.
我们不做硬数学。
In sorting, if you have integers going into your sort,
在排序中，如果要输入整数
you only do integer operations.
您只能执行整数运算。
You don't do anything math beyond them.
除了它们，您什么也不会做。
So what we do is we've broken up the keys
因此，我们要做的是分解密钥
into d digits for a reason.
变成d位数字是有原因的。
We're going to have d rounds in the sort.
我们将进行d回合。
And in each round, we're going to take all the keys
在每一轮中，我们将掌握所有关键
that we have.
我们有。
And we're going to sort them according to one of the digits.
我们将根据数字之一对它们进行排序。
So in one round, we'll sort them according to this digit.
因此，在一轮中，我们将根据该数字对其进行排序。
In one round, we'll sort them according
在一轮中，我们将根据
to this digit, this digit, this digit.
到这个数字，这个数字，这个数字。
Which digit do we start with?
我们以哪个数字开头？
What do you guys think?
你们有什么感想？
AUDIENCE: To least significant digit, right?
听众：最低有效位数，对不对？
AUDIENCE: And most significant on the left.
听众：最重要的在左边。
VICTOR COSTAN: So this or this?
维克多·科斯坦：那么这个还是这个？
AUDIENCE: The right side.
听众：右边。
AUDIENCE: 100 is bigger than 1, even
听众：100大于1，甚至
though the 1 is greater than the 0 in 100.
尽管1大于100中的0。
VICTOR COSTAN: You're helping me out.
维克多·科斯坦：您正在帮助我。
So the point I'm trying to make here
所以我要在这里提出的要点
is radix sort is unintuitive.
是基数排序是不直观的。
If we ask you on a quiz what do you start with,
如果我们在测验中问您从什么开始，
your intuition will tell you to start
你的直觉会告诉你开始
with the most significant digit.
最高有效位数。
Go against it.
反对它。
In radix sort, you start with the least significant digit
在基数排序中，您从最低有效数字开始
and then move your way out.
然后走出自己的路。
So radix sort goes like this.
所以基数排序是这样的。
AUDIENCE: I mean, it does make sense,
听众：我的意思是，这确实有道理，
because you don't have very much information unless you're
因为除非您
looking at bits.
看着位。
You can get a bunch of twos, but that
你可以得到一堆二，但那
doesn't give you much information.
没有给您太多信息。
The most information is the smallest bit.
信息最多的是最小的位。
And then you move up from there.
然后您从那里向上移动。
VICTOR COSTAN: It depends what information
VICTOR COSTAN：这取决于哪些信息
you're trying to get.
你想得到。
But maybe you know the algorithm, so you're thinking,
但是也许您知道算法，所以您在考虑，
oh, by knowing the algorithm, I know
哦，通过了解算法，我知道
that I'll have the most information
我将获得最多的信息
by looking at it this way.
通过这种方式看它。
All right, so let's sort these by the last digit.
好吧，让我们按最后一位排序。
Sweet.
甜。
Let's sort them by the digit, by the digit
让我们按数字，数字对它们进行排序
before the last digit.
最后一位之前。
What do I have to do in my sorting?
排序时我该怎么办？
What do I have to pay attention to?
我要注意什么？
So the sorting method that I use has to have a property.
因此，我使用的排序方法必须具有一个属性。
It can't be any kind of sorting.
不能进行任何排序。
Stable.
稳定。
So the reason we went through all this pain in counting sort
所以我们在计算排序时经历了所有这些痛苦的原因
is because we want to have a stable sort here.
是因为我们希望在这里有一个稳定的排序。
Now, let's try to sort these in a stable manner.
现在，让我们尝试以稳定的方式对它们进行排序。
This is the first one, two, four, one, three.
这是第一个，两个，四个，一个，三个。
Then I have two threes, so one, four, three, two, one, two,
然后我有两个三，所以一，四，三，二，一，二
three, four.
三四。
And then I have three fours.
然后我有三个四分之一。
Two, three, four, one.
二，三，四，一。
Two, four, one, three.
二，四，一，三
Two, one, four, three.
二，一，四，三
Way this isn't good.
这样不好。
Two, three, four, one.
二，三，四，一。
One, two, four, three.
一二三四
AUDIENCE: You should cross them off if you write them down.
听众：如果将它们写下来，则应将其划掉。
VICTOR COSTAN: I should.
维克多·科斯坦：我应该。
I was hoping you guys would help me if I mess up.
我希望你们能帮上我的忙。
So now these are sorted stably.
因此，现在这些已稳定地排序。
Let's look at these last three that have the same digit here.
让我们看看这最后三个具有相同数字的数字。
So they have the same four.
因此它们具有相同的四个。
If you look at the last digit, because I
如果你看最后一位数字，因为我
used a stable sorting, they're also
使用了稳定的排序，
sorted according to this last digit.
根据最后一位排序。
So they're sorted according to these last two digits,
因此，它们是根据最后两位数字排序的，
because the sorting that I used is stable.
因为我使用的排序是稳定的。
So now if I sort according to this digit,
所以现在如果我按照这个数字排序，
then if my sorting is stable, they're
如果我的排序稳定，那么他们
going to be sorted according to the last three digits.
将根据最后三位数进行排序。
So as I go from my last digit to my first digit,
因此，当我从最后一位转到第一位时，
the keys are going to be sorted according
键将根据
to the last digit, the last two digits, the last three
到最后一位数字，最后两位数字，最后三个
digits, and then all the way up to everything.
数字，然后一直到所有内容。
This is why I need a stable sort.
这就是为什么我需要一种稳定的排序方式。
And also, this is why I need to start from the end.
而且，这就是为什么我需要从头开始。
Does this make some sense?
这有意义吗？
What stable sort did we just learn?
我们刚刚学到了什么稳定的排序？
AUDIENCE: Counting.
听众：数数。
VICTOR COSTAN: Counting sort.
维克多·科斯坦：计数排序。
All right.
好吧。
So we're going to use counting sort for this.
因此，我们将为此使用计数排序。
What's the running time for one round?
一轮的时间是多少？
So for one sorting.
因此，进行一种排序。
One counting sort takes how much time?
一种计数需要花费多少时间？
AUDIENCE: This is a radix sort.
听众：这是一个基数排序。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yes.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
So radix sort is d rounds of counting sort.
因此，基数排序是d轮计数排序。
Count sort this, count sort this,
算一下，算一下，
count sort this, count sort this.
算一下，算一下。
So one round, one counting sort, what's the running time?
那么一轮，一种计数，运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: Thank you.
维克多·科斯坦：谢谢。
Now how about d of these plus the running time?
现在，其中的d和运行时间如何？
AUDIENCE: dn plus b.
听众：dn加b。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, but I want to come back here.
维克多·科斯坦：好的，但是我想回到这里。
And I want to be able to say that radix sort is optimal.
我想说基数排序是最佳的。
I want to be able to say that it is order n.
我想可以说这是n阶。
So what do I have to do in order to be able to say that?
那么，我必须做什么才能这样说？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] k equal to m.
听众：[听不清] k等于m。
VICTOR COSTAN: So you're going from-- you know the answer.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：所以您要走了，您就知道答案了。
You're going from the fact that you know the answer.
您从知道答案的事实出发。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, very good.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，很好。
What if we wouldn't know the answer?
如果我们不知道答案怎么办？
What do I need to do?
我需要做什么？
AUDIENCE: Well, we know the first part is order n.
听众：好吧，我们知道第一部分是n阶。
So--
所以 -
VICTOR COSTAN: So d has to be--
维克多·科斯坦：所以必须-
AUDIENCE: We want dn to be greater than dk, right?
听众：我们希望dn大于dk，对不对？
VICTOR COSTAN: Well, so dn.
维克多·科斯坦：恩，所以。
dn has to be, at most, o of n, right.
dn最多只能是n个中的o个。
Because otherwise, the whole thing would go above.
因为否则，整个事情将会超越。
So that wouldn't work.
所以那是行不通的。
So then what can I say about d?
那么关于d我能说什么呢？
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
VICTOR COSTAN: Very good.
VICTOR COSTAN：很好。
And how do you write constants in math mode?
以及如何在数学模式下编写常数？
AUDIENCE: Order one.
听众：第一。
VICTOR COSTAN: Very good.
VICTOR COSTAN：很好。
So d has to be order one.
因此，d必须为一。
Otherwise, it's not going to come out to that.
否则，就不会出现这种情况。
Now, what else do we know?
现在，我们还知道什么？
We have this that's order n plus k.
我们的阶次为n加k。
If I said this to be a lot smaller than k,
如果我说这个比k小很多，
if I set it to be log n, it's going to be order n.
如果我将其设置为log n，则将为n。
If I set it k to be a constant, if I use bits,
如果我将k设置为常数，如果我使用位，
if I use base 2-- so I said k equal 2-- this is still
如果我使用基数2--所以我说k等于2-这仍然是
going to be order n.
将被命令n。
So if k goes way below n, this step
因此，如果k低于n，则此步骤
is still going to be order n.
仍然是订单n。
So I might as well set k as high as possible.
所以我可能将k设置得尽可能高。
So k is order n, because that's the highest
所以k是n阶，因为那是最高的
thing I could set it to.
我可以将其设置为。
Now why do I want to do that?
现在为什么要这样做？
Yes, you have a ques--
是的，您有疑问-
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] represent in counting sort again?
听众：[听不清]又在计数排序中代表？
The length of what?
长度是多少？
VICTOR COSTAN: So in counting sort,
VICTOR COSTAN：因此，从数量上来说，
n is your input, how many keys you have.
n是您的输入，即您有多少个键。
And k is the size of this array.
k是此数组的大小。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
VICTOR COSTAN: So you have to be able to map
VICTOR COSTAN：因此，您必须能够绘制地图
your keys from 0 to k minus 1.
您的密钥从0到k减1。
AUDIENCE: It's set by n, basically.
听众：基本上由n设置。
Or it's set by the elements.
或者由元素设置。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
It's set by the nature of the keys.
它由按键的性质设置。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
Got it.
得到它了。
VICTOR COSTAN: So in real life, we're
维克多·科斯坦：在现实生活中，我们
thinking maybe we have some huge numbers that we want to sort.
想也许我们有一些我们想排序的数字。
And we're going to chunk them up into-- when we're
当我们将
writing on the board, we always have
在黑板上写字，我们总是
to chunk them up in base 10 digits,
将它们以10位为基数
because that's the only way we know how to write.
因为那是我们知道怎么写的唯一方法。
But in a computer memory, we can chunk them up into, say,
但是在计算机内存中，我们可以将它们分成例如
base 10,000 digits.
基本10,000位数。
And the fewer digits you have, the faster
位数越少越快
this is going to run.
这将要运行。
So we have to figure out what's the base.
因此，我们必须找出基础。
And it turns out that if you want
事实证明，如果你想
to have radix sort run in order and time, well,
让基数排序按时间顺序运行
the number of digits has to be sort of constant.
数字位数必须是常数。
I know that k should be order n, because I
我知道k应该是n阶，因为我
have no interest in making it lower than that.
没有兴趣使其低于此值。
So these two bounds together tell me
所以这两个界限一起告诉我
that the keys that I can sort are from zero
我可以排序的键从零开始
up to order n of order one.
直到第一阶的n。
And this looks terrible, but what it comes up to
这看起来很糟糕，但是结果如何
is that you can sort keys that look
是您可以对看起来像
like n to some constant for any constant.
像n到某个常数。
So you can sort huge keys, as long as huge still
因此，您可以对大型键进行排序，只要仍然
means finite.
表示有限。
And as long as you can figure out how to map them to numbers.
并且只要您能弄清楚如何将它们映射到数字。
Does this make some sense?
这有意义吗？
Would we ever want to use merge sort instead of counting sort?
我们是否要使用合并排序而不是计数排序？
Suppose we had a stable merge sort.
假设我们有一个稳定的合并排序。
Would we want to use that instead of counting sort here?
我们要使用它而不是在此处计算排序吗？
What would happen?
会发生什么？
So suppose it's stable.
因此，假设它是稳定的。
So it's correct.
所以这是正确的。
The algorithm isn't going to blow up.
该算法不会爆炸。
What's the running time for merge sort?
合并排序的运行时间是多少？
So if I use a merge sort.
因此，如果我使用合并排序。
So if I use the merge sort, it's going to be d times n log n.
因此，如果使用合并排序，它将是d乘以n log n。
So no matter how small d is, I'm still
所以无论d多么小，我仍然
not running in linear time.
不在线性时间内运行。
So merge sort does not go well with radix sort.
因此，合并排序与基数排序不太匹配。
So from my end, we're pretty much done.
因此，从我的角度来看，我们已经完成了许多工作。
We started with n log n.
我们从n log n开始。
And we got to a sorting algorithm that's order n.
然后我们得到一个排序为n的排序算法。
We started at the beginning of [INAUDIBLE], saying
我们从[音频不清晰]的开头开始说
that the best thing we can do is omega--
我们能做的最好的事情就是欧米茄-
is that omega-- omega of n.
是那个欧米茄-n的欧米茄。
We got to that limit.
我们达到了那个极限。
We're happy.
很高兴。
We're going to be done with sorting.
我们将完成排序。
Any questions from you guys?
你们有什么问题吗？
That means everyone's confused, right?
那意味着每个人都很困惑，对吧？
Yes, thank you.
是的，谢谢。
AUDIENCE: Can you explain what the stability criteria
听众：您能解释一下稳定性标准吗
is again?
再来一次？
VICTOR COSTAN: The--
维克多·科斯坦：
AUDIENCE: Stability for these sorting algorithms.
听众：这些排序算法的稳定性。
Which ones are stable and what makes it unstable?
哪些是稳定的，什么使它不稳定？
VICTOR COSTAN: All right, very good.
维克多·科斯坦：好的，很好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So I like especially the last part,
所以我特别喜欢最后一部分，
with which ones are stable.
与哪些是稳定的。
I'd like to go through that.
我想经历一下。
So a stable sorting algorithm means
因此，稳定的排序算法意味着
that if you have two keys that are equal,
如果您有两个相等的键，
the key that shows up first in the input
输入中首先显示的键
is the key that is produced to the output.
是产生到输出的密钥。
So in this model, your keys are not necessarily integers.
因此，在此模型中，您的键不一定是整数。
Your keys might be those weird classes
你的钥匙可能是那些奇怪的类
that implement some method that maps them to integers.
实现一些将它们映射为整数的方法。
So say there is a method there, __int__,
所以说那里有一种方法，__ int__，
that gives you the integer for that.
给你的整数。
So the sorting algorithm would only see a three here.
因此，排序算法在这里只会看到3。
But in fact, this is a complex object.
但是实际上，这是一个复杂的对象。
And this is another complex object,
这是另一个复杂的对象，
but the sorting only sees the three.
但排序只能看到这三个。
If this guy shows up before this guy in the input,
如果此人在输入中出现在此人之前，
they have to show up in the same order in the output.
它们必须以相同的顺序出现在输出中。
AUDIENCE: Why would that be bad if they're switched?
听众：如果切换它们，那为什么会不好呢？
VICTOR COSTAN: It's not stable.
维克多·科斯坦：不稳定。
If they're switched, then when we're using a stable sorting
如果切换了它们，那么当我们使用稳定的排序时
algorithm here.
算法在这里。
So here, the key is this complicated object.
因此，这里的关键是这个复杂的对象。
But say we're in the second round.
但是说我们在第二轮。
We're in this round, which we played with.
我们在这一轮中，我们一起玩过。
Even though the key is this whole complicated object,
即使关键是整个复杂的对象，
the only thing that the counting sort sees is this number.
计数排序唯一看到的就是这个数字。
So this guy looks like three.
所以这个家伙看起来像三个。
This guy looks like three.
这个家伙看起来像三个。
And these three guys, although they're different,
这三个家伙，尽管他们不同，
they look like four.
他们看起来像四个。
If I don't output them in the right order--
如果我的输出顺序不正确，
say I output this one all the way at the end-- then
说我一路输出到最后-然后
I'm going to get two, three, four, one to be down here.
我将得到两个，三个，四个，一个在这里。
And now my numbers aren't sorted by the last two digits anymore.
现在我的电话号码不再按最后两位数字排序。
So it breaks any algorithm that assumes stability.
因此，它破坏了任何假定稳定性的算法。
So stability is something that you get from a sort,
因此，稳定性是您从某种程度上获得的，
because it's convenient to assume it
因为假设它很方便
in some other algorithm that builds up on that sort.
在其他基于这种算法的算法中
If you don't need it, you don't care about it.
如果您不需要它，则无需关心。
But in some cases, you need it.
但是在某些情况下，您需要它。
And for the second part, which algorithms are stable.
第二部分，哪些算法是稳定的。
Is insertion sort stable?
插入排序稳定吗？
AUDIENCE: I assume so.
听众：我想是的。
I mean, stable is being correct, right?
我的意思是，稳定是正确的，对吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: No.
维克多·科斯坦：不。
We mean that property there.
我们的意思是那里的财产。
AUDIENCE: Oh, I see.
听众：哦，我知道了。
You mean in order.
你的意思是为了秩序。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
Insertion sort goes in order.
插入排序按顺序进行。
But I guess it could push other things out of order.
但是我想这可能会使其他事情乱七八糟。
VICTOR COSTAN: So insertion sort,
VICTOR COSTAN：所以插入排序，
you're doing swapping to move things to the left.
您正在交换以将事物向左移动。
But if you find two things that are equal,
但是，如果您发现两个相等的事物，
you're never going to swap them.
您将永远不会交换它们。
So insertion sort is in order, is stable.
因此插入排序是有序的，稳定的。
Merge sort, the one we gave you in that list is not stable.
合并排序后，我们在该列表中给您的排序不稳定。
But there is the one character change that makes it stable.
但是有一个字符更改使它稳定。
And you should look at today's lecture notes
您应该看一下今天的讲义
to find out what that is.
找出是什么。
So merge sort can be stable.
因此合并排序可以是稳定的。
Heapsort, stable or unstable?
堆排序，稳定还是不稳定？
Unstable.
不稳定
And there's a really small example
有一个非常小的例子
that you should look at.
你应该看看。
Counting sort, stable or unstable?
计数排序，稳定还是不稳定？
AUDIENCE: Stable.
听众：稳定。
VICTOR COSTAN: Thank you.
维克多·科斯坦：谢谢。
It would have broken my heart if this would have come out wrong.
如果这是错误的话，那会伤透我的心。
And radix sort?
和基数排序？
AUDIENCE: Probably.
听众：大概吧。
Yes.
是。
VICTOR COSTAN: Probably stable, right?
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：也许稳定吧？
All right.
好吧。
Any more questions?
还有其他问题吗？
I like that question by the way, because you made me do this.
顺便说一下，我喜欢这个问题，因为您让我这样做了。
I like that.
我喜欢。
Any more questions?
还有其他问题吗？
All right, thank you guys.
好的，谢谢大家。